=To Kill a Songbird=
=لقتل طائر مغرد=
(Adapted from Shen Xiaoguan's Bird Kills Seven People)
(مقتبس من رواية شين شياو غوان " طائر يقتل سبعة أشخاص")
=Episode 8= (No Honor Among Bandits)
=الحلقة 8= (لا شرف بين قطاع الطرق)
If you came to investigate this case,
إذا جئت للتحقيق في هذه القضية،
you're looking for the wrong man.
أنتِ تبحثين عن الرجل الخطأ.
The one who paid for a fake head
الشخص الذي دفع ثمن رأس مزيف
was Zhao Chengxi.
كان تشاو تشينغشي.
Zhao Chengxi.
تشاو تشنغشي.
He's who you should be after.
هو الشخص الذي يجب أن تسعى إليه.
Too bad
سيئة للغاية
you won't live to see another day.
لن تعيش لترى يوماً آخر.
Die!
ال!
(In the third month)
(في الشهر الثالث)
(of the fifth year of Chongning,)
(من السنة الخامسة من عهد تشونغنينغ،)
(Huang Baocheng starved his father Huang Agen to death,)
(هوانغ باوتشنغ تسبب في موت والده هوانغ أغين جوعاً،)
(severed his head,)
(قطع رأسه)
(branded it with a false mark, and buried it at Qili Slope.)
(وضع عليها علامة مزيفة، ودفنها في منحدر كيلي.)
(He acted under orders)
(لقد تصرف بناءً على أوامر)
(from a man named Zhao Chengxi,)
(من رجل يُدعى تشاو تشنغشي،)
(who paid him in silver)
(الذي دفع له بالفضة)
(to do it.)
(للقيام بذلك.)
He won't wake up for another six to ten hours.
لن يستيقظ لمدة تتراوح بين ست إلى عشر ساعات أخرى.
Keep the confession with you.
احتفظ بالاعتراف معك.
Why did you rush out?
لماذا خرجت مسرعاً؟
You saw me signal you to stop.
لقد رأيتني أشير إليك بالتوقف.
Were you trying to get yourself killed?
هل كنت تحاول أن تقتل نفسك؟
I saw it.
رأيته.
But I don't take orders from you.
لكنني لا أتلقى أوامر منك.
Indeed.
بالفعل.
You're the last person who needs to listen to me.
أنت آخر شخص يحتاج إلى الاستماع إليّ.
You prefer County Magistrate Jiang over me.
أنت تفضل قاضي المقاطعة جيانغ عليّ.
You only listen to him.
أنت تستمع إليه فقط.
Well, now look at us.
حسناً، انظر إلينا الآن.
We're stuck at the foot of the mountain.
نحن عالقون عند سفح الجبل.
We'll have to wait for the rain to stop before we can go back up.
سيتعين علينا الانتظار حتى يتوقف المطر قبل أن نتمكن من العودة إلى الأعلى.
(You and her)
(أنت وهي)
(were poisoned.)
(تسمموا).
(You risked your life to feed her the antidote,)
(لقد خاطرت بحياتك لإطعامها الترياق،)
(yet she didn't appreciate it at all.)
(لكنها لم تُقدّر ذلك على الإطلاق.)
Why did you give me the antidote?
لماذا أعطيتني الترياق؟
You deliberately used yourself as bait
لقد استخدمت نفسك كطعم عن عمد
to lure Huang Baocheng out and trick him into confessing, didn't you?
أليس هدفك استدراج هوانغ باوتشنغ وخداعه للاعتراف؟
This is my case.
هذه هي حالتي.
You didn't have to go that far.
لم يكن عليك أن تذهب إلى هذا الحد.
You have a blessed life.
أنت تتمتع بحياة مباركة.
You're the disciple of the chancellor.
أنت تلميذ المستشار.
You have a brilliant future ahead.
أمامك مستقبل باهر.
Yet you risked your life for this case.
ومع ذلك فقد خاطرت بحياتك من أجل هذه القضية.
Don't tell me
لا تخبرني
you've taken a liking to me.
لقد أعجبت بي.
I favor well-bred ladies
أفضّل السيدات ذوات النسب الرفيع
from respectable families,
من عائلات محترمة،
as well as gentle, soft-spoken women.
وكذلك النساء اللطيفات ذوات الكلام الهادئ.
However, I've no interest in temperamental lunatics.
لكني لا أهتم بالمجانين ذوي المزاج المتقلب.
Investigating cases and eradicating criminals
التحقيق في القضايا والقضاء على المجرمين
are my duties.
هذه هي واجباتي.
Don't overthink it
لا تبالغ في التفكير في الأمر
and make trouble for yourself.
وتسبب لنفسك المتاعب.
And one more thing…
وشيء آخر...
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
I'm testing whether you meant
أنا أختبر ما إذا كنت تقصد
what you just said.
ما قلته للتو.
And what's the verdict?
وما هو الحكم النهائي؟
Your breathing's steady. Your heartbeat's normal.
تنفسك منتظم. نبضات قلبك طبيعية.
You were telling the truth.
كنت تقول الحقيقة.
Good.
جيد.
Where'd you learn such a lowly trick?
من أين تعلمت هذه الحيلة الدنيئة؟
Don't go trying it on anyone else.
لا تجرب ذلك على أي شخص آخر.
You might just…
قد تفعل ذلك فقط...
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
Tomorrow, I'll…
غداً سأفعل...
By tomorrow, you'll already be dead.
بحلول الغد، ستكون قد مت بالفعل.
♪You stepped ahead of the wind♪
♪لقد سبقت الريح♪
This is the only thing I've got left that'll work.
هذا هو الشيء الوحيد المتبقي لدي والذي سينجح.
Within a quarter of an hour, it'll stir certain thoughts and desires,
في غضون ربع ساعة، سيثير ذلك أفكاراً ورغبات معينة،
and force the poison out through sweat.
وإخراج السم عن طريق العرق.
♪Unsure, unaware♪
♪غير متأكد، غير مدرك♪
♪You crossed rivers beneath your umbrella♪
♪عبرتَ الأنهار تحت مظلتك♪
♪Yet no one came to keep the promise♪
♪لكن لم يأتِ أحدٌ للوفاء بالوعد♪
♪Across snow and mountains without end♪
♪عبر الثلج والجبال التي لا نهاية لها♪
♪Unknowing, unawakened♪
♪غير مدرك، غير مستيقظ♪
♪This love brings tears to our brows♪
♪هذا الحب يُذرف الدموع من جباهنا♪
♪The zither falls silent, the ink left longing♪
♪صمتت آلة الزيثارة، وبقي الحبر متلهفاً♪
♪Had we never met♪
♪لو لم نلتقِ أبدًا♪
♪This obsession would not exist, we'd never meet again♪
♪لم يكن هذا الهوس ليوجد، ولن نلتقي مجدداً♪
♪Had I known one look could bind my life♪
لو كنت أعلم أن نظرة واحدة قد تقسم حياتي!
♪I would've turned away at first sight♪
♪كنت سأبتعد من النظرة الأولى♪
♪Tears fall at my fingertips, love coiled into a sleepless song♪
♪تتساقط الدموع على أطراف أصابعي، والحب يلتف في أغنية لا تنام♪
♪In this fleeting life, who will sing the final note?♪
♪في هذه الحياة الفانية، من سيغني النوتة الأخيرة؟♪
♪In the end, it's nothing but goodbye♪
♪في النهاية، ليس الأمر سوى وداع♪
♪Only the snow stays behind♪
♪لا يبقى سوى الثلج♪
♪Falling, year after year♪
♪يسقطون، عاماً بعد عام♪
Don't look at me.
لا تنظر إليّ.
Stay still.
ابقَ ساكناً.
Don't touch me.
لا تلمسني.
The Blended Harmony incense is meant to make you feverish, sweat,
يهدف بخور "بليندِد هارموني" إلى جعلك تشعر بالحمى والتعرق.
and to let your instinct take over.
وأن تدع غريزتك تتولى زمام الأمور.
Why isn't it working?
لماذا لا يعمل؟
I need you to follow your heart right now.
أحتاج منك أن تتبع قلبك الآن.
Is there anything you want to do?
هل هناك أي شيء ترغب في القيام به؟
All
الجميع
you want to do is comb my hair?
هل كل ما تريد فعله هو تمشيط شعري؟
It looks like a pile of straw.
يبدو وكأنه كومة من القش.
Hurts my eyes just looking at it.
يؤلمني النظر إليه.
Anyone can tell you don't bother taking care of it.
بإمكان أي شخص أن يخبرك ألا تهتم به.
You're nothing like the other ladies.
أنتِ لا تشبهين السيدات الأخريات على الإطلاق.
You should've been like them.
كان ينبغي أن تكون مثلهم.
We found them!
لقد وجدناهم!
They're here!
لقد وصلوا!
Get the carriage up here!
أحضر العربة إلى هنا!
Master Lu's badly injured!
أصيب المعلم لو بجروح بالغة!
(Gathering Auspiciousness With the Sun)
(جمع الحظ السعيد مع الشمس)
Once there were two brothers,
كان هناك ذات مرة شقيقان،
both greedy for money and power.
كلاهما جشع للمال والسلطة.
The elder brother, for the sake of wealth,
الأخ الأكبر، من أجل الثروة،
could even starve his own father to death.
بل إنه قد يتسبب في موت والده جوعاً.
What he didn't know was that
ما لم يكن يعلمه هو أن
his younger brother,
شقيقه الأصغر،
who appeared indecisive and harmless,
الذي بدا مترددًا وغير مؤذٍ،
had an even more vicious heart.
كان قلبه أكثر شراسة.
Their father hadn't died of starvation.
لم يمت والدهم جوعاً.
He was poisoned by the younger brother.
لقد سُمِّم على يد شقيقه الأصغر.
That's why his face turned
ولهذا السبب تحول وجهه
that terrifying shade of purple when he died.
ذلك اللون الأرجواني المرعب الذي ظهر عند وفاته.
Years later,
بعد سنوات،
someone in the stronghold was poisoned the same way.
تعرض شخص ما في المعقل للتسمم بنفس الطريقة.
When the elder brother saw it, he came up with a plan
عندما رآه الأخ الأكبر، وضع خطة
and chopped off those men's heads.
وقطع رؤوس هؤلاء الرجال.
The younger brother saw this and came up with a plan of his own.
رأى الأخ الأصغر ذلك ، فوضع خطة خاصة به.
He played the madman
لقد لعب دور الرجل المجنون
and set up the Zhong Kui tale of devouring men,
ووضع قصة تشونغ كوي عن التهام الرجال،
all so he could later
كل ذلك حتى يتمكن من ذلك لاحقاً
frame his brother for the killings.
لفّق تهمة القتل لأخيه.
Once that happened, the entire stronghold
وبمجرد حدوث ذلك، أصبح الحصن بأكمله
would fall into the younger brother's hands.
سيقع في يد الأخ الأصغر.
Then, the authorities arrived.
ثم وصلت السلطات.
He planned everything with great care.
لقد خطط لكل شيء بعناية فائقة.
Meticulously,
بدقة متناهية،
he pinned the crimes
لقد حمّل الجرائم المسؤولية
and fake evidence on his brother.
وتلفيق أدلة ضد شقيقه.
He had gone mad, after all.
لقد جنّ جنونه، في نهاية المطاف.
At worst, he'd be an accomplice.
في أسوأ الأحوال، سيكون شريكاً في الجريمة.
Isn't that right, Huang Baotian?
أليس هذا صحيحاً يا هوانغ باوتيان؟
Huang Baotian.
هوانغ باوتيان.
You set me up!
لقد نصبت لي فخاً!
(It was the eighth year of Zhenghe.)
(كان ذلك في السنة الثامنة من حكم تشنغخه.)
(The 29th day of the 5th month.)
(اليوم التاسع والعشرون من الشهر الخامس.)
(It was drizzling.)
(كان الجو ممطراً قليلاً.)
(No sun in sight,)
(لا توجد شمس في الأفق،)
(yet life bloomed silently.)
(ومع ذلك، ازدهرت الحياة في صمت.)
(Nine days until the seventh day of the sixth month)
(تسعة أيام حتى اليوم السابع من الشهر السادس)
(To die by your greed)
(أن تموت بسبب جشعك)
(is the ending you deserved.)
(هذه هي النهاية التي تستحقها.)
I knew you'd go looking for those brothers.
كنت أعرف أنك ستذهب للبحث عن هؤلاء الإخوة.
Watching them go through questioning
مشاهدتهم وهم يخضعون للاستجواب
so numb and painless
مخدرة وغير مؤلمة
didn't sit right with me.
لم يرق لي ذلك.
I only told a few truths.
لم أقل سوى بعض الحقائق.
I didn't kill anyone.
لم أقتل أحداً.
That's hardly a crime.
هذا ليس جريمة على الإطلاق.
If I ever killed someone,
لو قتلت شخصاً ما يوماً ما،
would you take me in?
هل ستستقبلني في منزلك؟
Where are you going?
إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟
To find Master Jiang
للعثور على المعلم جيانغ
and ask him to help me look into Zhao Chengxi.
واطلب منه أن يساعدني في التحقيق في أمر تشاو تشنغشي.
Sir, a hatred that cuts to the bone
يا سيدي، كراهية تخترق العظم
is something you've probably never experienced in your life.
هو شيء ربما لم تختبره في حياتك قط.
You wouldn't understand why I'd risk everything
لن تفهم لماذا سأخاطر بكل شيء
just to fight for the truth.
فقط للنضال من أجل الحقيقة.
I see you've disregarded all propriety with me.
أرى أنك تجاهلت كل قواعد اللياقة معي.
You don't trust me, and you've no interest
أنت لا تثق بي، وليس لديك أي اهتمام.
in a madwoman like me.
في امرأة مجنونة مثلي.
What do I have to fear?
ما الذي يجب أن أخشاه؟
Does your maid
هل خادمتك
not know about your condition?
لا تعلم بحالتك؟
Why don't you have her perform the acupuncture for you?
لماذا لا تطلب منها أن تقوم بإجراء الوخز بالإبر لك؟
No one knows about it except you.
لا أحد يعلم بذلك سواك.
Brother…
أخ…
(A hatred that cuts to the bone.)
(كراهية تصل إلى العظم.)
(I have one as well.)
(لدي واحدة أيضاً.)
(I favor well-bred ladies)
(أفضّل السيدات ذوات النسب الرفيع)
(from respectable families,)
(من عائلات محترمة،)
(as well as gentle, soft-spoken women.)
(وكذلك النساء اللطيفات ذوات الكلام الرقيق).
(However, I've no interest in temperamental lunatics.)
(مع ذلك، ليس لدي أي اهتمام بالمجانين ذوي المزاج المتقلب.)
(Investigating cases and eradicating criminals are my duties.)
(التحقيق في القضايا والقضاء على المجرمين من واجباتي.)
(Don't overthink it)
(لا تبالغ في التفكير)
(and make trouble for yourself.)
(وتسبب لنفسك بالمتاعب.)
Magistrate Lu,
القاضي لو،
the Huang brothers are dead.
توفي الأخوان هوانغ.
♪A thrush's song pierced the endless night♪
♪اخترق غناء طائر الشحرور الليل الذي لا ينتهي♪
♪Blood splattered on the bamboo cage, reflecting the cool moonlight♪
♪ دماء متناثرة على قفص الخيزران، تعكس ضوء القمر البارد ♪
♪Thirteen years of frost and snow sealed the old study window♪
♪ثلاثة عشر عامًا من الصقيع والثلج أغلقت نافذة غرفة الدراسة القديمة♪
♪I twisted the needle, prying open the past♪
♪لففتُ الإبرة، كاشفاً الماضي♪
♪A cold stone marrow presses against my palm♪
♪يضغط نخاع حجري بارد على راحة يدي♪
♪My older brother lay buried afar♪
♪يرقد أخي الأكبر مدفوناً في مكان بعيد♪
♪Flames licked across that place♪
♪تشتعل النيران في ذلك المكان♪
♪A list of righteous hearts♪
♪قائمة بالقلوب الصالحة♪
♪Who laughed in the dark at the panic?♪
♪ من ضحك في الظلام على الذعر؟ ♪
♪I'm the shadow caged within as well as the flying light♪
♪أنا الظل المحبوس في الداخل، وكذلك الضوء الطائر♪
♪Only when hatred burns out did we know how scorching our obsessions were♪
♪فقط عندما انطفأت جذوة الكراهية أدركنا مدى لهيب هواجسنا♪
♪You said you'd die if you hit a stone♪
♪قلتَ إنك ستموت إذا اصطدمتَ بحجر♪
♪Yet you crashed into my fate's web♪
♪لكنك اصطدمت بشبكة قدري♪
♪Pear blossoms fell all over the wound on your shoulder♪
♪تساقطت أزهار الكمثرى على الجرح الموجود على كتفك♪
♪The wind in the bamboo forest dispersed the hexagrams♪
♪ هبّت الرياح في غابة الخيزران فشتّتت الأشكال السداسية ♪
♪The thrush carried the past away♪
♪حمل طائر السمنة الماضي بعيدًا♪
♪I stood at the end of the fireworks and gaze♪
وقفتُ عند نهاية الألعاب النارية ونظرتُ إليها.
♪You lifted a lantern to illuminate♪
♪رفعتَ فانوسًا لتنيره♪
♪That page♪
♪تلك الصفحة♪